LAUREN HIGHTOWER

LHIGHTOWER@VERSATILECONTENT.COM | 404.234.0194 | 1859 BRADLEY GIN RD MONROE, GA. 30656

LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS

JavaScript React

Node.js

ASP.Net

CSS

HTML

REST Api

GraphQL

DATABASES

Microsoft SQL Server

MongoDB

DynamoDB

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE &

CUSTOMER DATA PLATFORMS

Power BI

Salesforce

CLOUD PLATFORMS

Amazon Web Services

(AWS)

Azure Cloud

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

AWS Amplify

Jira

Visual Code

Docker

DATA FORMATS

JSON

XML

CSV

Excel

Tab Delimited

SUMMARY

I am a Technical Solution Architect and Engineer creating data and content-based solutions for the past 20+ years. I have worked as a solo engineer and lead teams of developers in implementing solutions. I have also served as the face of the development effort to non-technical teams including C-level executives, marketers, product owners, and end users.

I am committed to crafting the best solutions for clients in a holistic fashion — understanding the broad scope of a client's business to develop strategic solutions that fit within the larger framework of their technical ecosystem.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Technical Architect, Washington Post / Arc XP, July 2021 - present Develop technical solutions for bringing together data and content from disparate system into a single repository for distribution to multiple channels. My responsibilities include:

- meeting and establishing a rapport with potential clients.
- demonstrating the technical features of Arc XP and how they can increase user engagement while driving down costs.
- understanding and documenting existing client technology ecosystems.
- presenting solution architecture diagrams integrating Arc XP into the client ecosystems.
- planning and executing data migrations and data synchronizations across systems.
- serving as scrum master on larger projects that require a team of developers, project managers and quality assurance analysts.

Sitecore Technical Architect, Tag, June 2019 - August 2021

Developed Sitecore solutions for a large healthcare company to communicate results of drug trial results and effectiveness to consumers and health care providers.

- Led a team of ~15 developers, project managers, and quality assurance analysts
- · Represented the team in leadership and planning meetings
- Presented designs, architecture diagrams
- Introduced new innovations in streamlining the content curation and deployment process in a highly-regulated industry

Founder and CEO, Ivey House Development, Nov 2004 - June 2019 Developed webbased Sitecore solutions using C#, ASP.Net, SQL Server, jQuery, Javascript, HTML, and CSS.

- Led business development and sales presentations to potential customers for projects ranging from \$100k - \$600k
- Increased business year over year by an average of 15%
- Ensured projects were profitable and delivered on time
- Led teams of 3-15 developers, project managers and quality assurance analysts
- Served as Product Owner and Scrum Master for ongoing projects
- Architected and developed software applications to meet the diverse needs of clients

EDUCATION

University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA — BA, 1991